[
    {
        "Question":"A 73-year-old male patient is under the follow up in the claudication clinic and  was managed by the best medical treatment. Recently during his last visit, he  reported that he started to develop leg pain after walking 600 yard which is  worse than before, and he also has calf pain during nights. On examinations,  there is no palpable pedal pulses, feet are warm, and CRT is 3 sec. What is the  most accepted diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Restless leg syndrome",
        "Option 2":"Critical limb ischemia",
        "Option 3":"Chronic venous insufficiency",
        "Option 4":"Acute limb Ischemia",
        "Option 5":"Spinal canal stenosis",
        "Correct Answer":"Critical limb ischemia"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 74-year-old, man presents with a pulsatile swelling in his abdomen, and he was  diagnosed as aortic dissection. What is the principal abnormality within the wall  aorta?",
        "Option 1":"Adventitial collagen",
        "Option 2":"Adventitial elastin",
        "Option 3":"Medial collagen",
        "Option 4":"Intimal elastin",
        "Option 5":"Medial elastin",
        "Correct Answer":"Intimal elastin"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following is not considered as a risk factor for aortic dissection?",
        "Option 1":"Hypertension",
        "Option 2":"Pregnancy",
        "Option 3":"Atherosclerosis",
        "Option 4":"Diabetes mellites",
        "Option 5":"Smoking",
        "Correct Answer":"Diabetes mellites"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the mechanism of action of the rivaroxaban?",
        "Option 1":"Vitamin K inhibitor",
        "Option 2":"Direct factor Xa inhibitor",
        "Option 3":"Thrombin inhibitor",
        "Option 4":"Antiplatelet",
        "Option 5":"Inhibit growth factor",
        "Correct Answer":"Direct factor Xa inhibitor"
    },
    {
        "Question":"When to stop apixaban before surgery?",
        "Option 1":"24 hours",
        "Option 2":"2-3 days",
        "Option 3":"7 days",
        "Option 4":"12 hours",
        "Option 5":"5 days",
        "Correct Answer":"2-3 days"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 92-bedbound lady with DM, CKD and ischemic cardiomyopathy presented to  your clinic complaining of bilateral calf pain. CTA showed lower aortic and bilateral CIA occlusion. What is the best management?",
        "Option 1":"Angioplasty",
        "Option 2":"Angioplasty and stenting",
        "Option 3":"Palliation with pain management",
        "Option 4":"Bilateral above knee amputation",
        "Option 5":"Aorto-bifemoral",
        "Correct Answer":"Palliation with pain management"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the mechanism of action of Tranexamic acid?",
        "Option 1":"Inhibits thrombin",
        "Option 2":"Inhibits of factor Xa",
        "Option 3":"Inhibits plasmin",
        "Option 4":"Antiplatelet",
        "Option 5":"Increase the RBC",
        "Correct Answer":"Inhibits plasmin"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 72year old male with AF and diabetes in addition to a previous history of EVAR  repair for AAA 3 months ago. Today the patient is complaining of trash foot.  What is the most probable source?",
        "Option 1":"Thrombosed EVAR stent",
        "Option 2":"Popliteal aneurysm",
        "Option 3":"New thrombosis",
        "Option 4":"Femoral stent thrombosis",
        "Option 5":"Abdominal aortic aneurysm",
        "Correct Answer":"Thrombosed EVAR stent"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 56-year-old diabetic male presented with painful foot ulcer, by examination he  has no bilateral peripheral pulsation. Patient has a history of renal impairment.  What is the best investigation for diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Doppler US",
        "Option 2":"Duplex scan",
        "Option 3":"Duplex with PSV measures",
        "Option 4":"CT angiography",
        "Option 5":"MRA",
        "Correct Answer":"Duplex with PSV measures"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 19 young guy comes into A&E after self-injury to his neck with a  Knife. Patient is breathing and talking fine, BP 80\/40 with severe bleeding from  neck. What is the best initial course of action?",
        "Option 1":"Pressure dressing",
        "Option 2":"Urgent surgical exploration",
        "Option 3":"Transfuse blood",
        "Option 4":"CT neck",
        "Option 5":"Endoscopic stenting",
        "Correct Answer":"Pressure dressing"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 60-year-old woman with a long-standing extensive varicose vein presented  with severe right leg pain on standing and walking. Which one of the following is  most likely to be due to her varicose vein disease?",
        "Option 1":"Blistering eruption on lower legs",
        "Option 2":"Dusky discoloration of toes",
        "Option 3":"Eczema around the ankle",
        "Option 4":"Splinter haemorrhages",
        "Option 5":"Ulceration of the dorsum of foot",
        "Correct Answer":"Eczema around the ankle"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 54-year-old patient with a non-specific medical history presented complaining of severe abdominal pain with collapse. He was diagnosed with ruptured abdominal aortic aneurysm  ,what is the best action?",
        "Option 1":"CT abdomen with contrast",
        "Option 2":"Urgent laparotomy",
        "Option 3":"Duplex ultrasound",
        "Option 4":"Best supportive care without intervention",
        "Option 5":"MRA",
        "Correct Answer":"Urgent laparotomy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the most common cause of acquired abdominal aortic aneurysm?",
        "Option 1":"Hypertension",
        "Option 2":"Fungal infection",
        "Option 3":"Marfan's syndrome",
        "Option 4":"Arthrosclerosis",
        "Option 5":"Congenital defect",
        "Correct Answer":"Arthrosclerosis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 12-year-old boy presented with acute severe headache. He was diagnosed with subarachnoid haemorrhage. What is the most common acceptable pathology of saccular aneurysm?",
        "Option 1":"Congenital wall weakness",
        "Option 2":"Mycotic aneurysm",
        "Option 3":"Hypertensive",
        "Option 4":"Atherosclerosis",
        "Option 5":"Hypertension",
        "Correct Answer":"Congenital wall weakness"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 63-year-old patient complained of calf claudication while walking a short  distance. On examination, there is a loss of tibial arteries pulses. What is the  most likely site of arterial occlusion?",
        "Option 1":"External iliac artery",
        "Option 2":"Common femoral artery",
        "Option 3":"Superficial femoral artery",
        "Option 4":"Popliteal artery",
        "Option 5":"Anterior tibial artery",
        "Correct Answer":"Superficial femoral artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 37-female presented with an ulcer on the medial malleolus with painless  skin changes around the ankle. She had a history of varicose vein repair 5 years  ago. Her ABI is normal. What is the most likely type of this ulcer?",
        "Option 1":"Infected eczema",
        "Option 2":"Venous ulcer",
        "Option 3":"Ischemic ulcer",
        "Option 4":"Malignant ulcer",
        "Option 5":"Neuropathic ulcer",
        "Correct Answer":"Venous ulcer"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 50-year-old male presented with a dry gangrene of fifth toe.  angiography revealed a long segment occlusion in the superficial femoral artery in addition to a patent runoff in the posterior tibial artery. What is the most appropriate management for this situation?",
        "Option 1":"Amputation of 5th toe",
        "Option 2":"Below knee amputation",
        "Option 3":"Medical management",
        "Option 4":"Femoro-distal bypass",
        "Option 5":"Angioplasty with stent insertion",
        "Correct Answer":"Femoro-distal bypass"
    },
    {
        "Question":"75-year-old patient was presented at the A&E with severe abdominal pain, and which is radiating to the back. On examination he has a blood pressure of 100-70 and heart rate of 80 with an obvious epigastric pulsating mass, what to do next?",
        "Option 1":"Immediate CTA",
        "Option 2":"Immediately transfer to open theatre",
        "Option 3":"Immediately transfer to hybrid theatre",
        "Option 4":"Follow up as outpatient",
        "Option 5":"PET scan",
        "Correct Answer":"Immediate CTA"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 55-year-old male presented by chronic ischemia. CT angiography  showed occlusion of both SFA and popliteal arteries, while anterior tibial is  functioning well what is the best management?",
        "Option 1":"Femoral distal graft",
        "Option 2":"Angioplasty",
        "Option 3":"Best medical treatment",
        "Option 4":"Amputation",
        "Option 5":"Follow up",
        "Correct Answer":"Femoral distal graft"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 61-year-old male with impaired cardiac function presented with bilateral  lower limb pain, and he diagnosed with bilateral common iliac occlusion. What  is the best intervention?",
        "Option 1":"Aortobifemoral",
        "Option 2":"Femrofemoral crossover",
        "Option 3":"Axillobifemoral",
        "Option 4":"Axillounifemoral",
        "Option 5":"Aortounifemoral",
        "Correct Answer":"Axillobifemoral"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient underwent aortic graft (device) done 3 years ago. The patient began to complain of left lower limb pain over the past 5 months, CT angiography showed blocked femoral anastomosis in the affected side. The other limb foot pulsation is intact. Patient began to develop dyspnea on exertion recently. What is the best intervention?",
        "Option 1":"Aorto femoral bypass",
        "Option 2":"Axillo femoral",
        "Option 3":"Femoro-femoral cross",
        "Option 4":"Acute embolectomy",
        "Option 5":"Femoro popliteal",
        "Correct Answer":"Femoro-femoral cross"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is giant cell arteritis main pathology?",
        "Option 1":"Granulomatous lesions",
        "Option 2":"No skip lesions.",
        "Option 3":"CD8 more than CD4",
        "Option 4":"External carotid arteritis",
        "Option 5":"Medium sized vasculitis",
        "Correct Answer":"Granulomatous lesions"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65-year-old male is diagnosed with Leriche syndrome. Which type of arterial  bypass should be used?",
        "Option 1":"Axillo-bifemoral",
        "Option 2":"Aorto-unifemoral",
        "Option 3":"Fem-pop bypass",
        "Option 4":"Aorto lliac bypass",
        "Option 5":"Aorto-bifemoral Bypass",
        "Correct Answer":"Aorto-bifemoral Bypass"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Lines of Zahn in histopathology is evidence of?",
        "Option 1":"Thrombus",
        "Option 2":"Atheroma",
        "Option 3":"Malignancy",
        "Option 4":"Abscess",
        "Option 5":"Necrosis",
        "Correct Answer":"Thrombus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the effect of smoking on blood vessels?",
        "Option 1":"Activate nicotinic receptor.",
        "Option 2":"Free radical attach to nitric oxide receptor",
        "Option 3":"Release of prostacyclin",
        "Option 4":"Inhibit myocyte proliferation",
        "Option 5":"Endothelial dysfunction",
        "Correct Answer":"Endothelial dysfunction"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65-year-old male underwent AAA repair, and he is now in ward for post- operative care. The nurse noticed that the patient was oliguric, and his urine is dark in color. Patient blood pressure was at 140-90 with pulse of 100 what is the best explanation for this?",
        "Option 1":"Normal Sequala post-surgery",
        "Option 2":"Pre-renal failure",
        "Option 3":"Toxicity from medication",
        "Option 4":"Clamping of the renal vessels during surgery",
        "Option 5":"Bladder necrosis",
        "Correct Answer":"Clamping of the renal vessels during surgery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"20-year-old typist was referred to your vascular center with a 2-week history of agonizing arm pain during work. On examination, she has no upper limb pulsation. Her ESR was elevated. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Polyarteritis nodosa",
        "Option 2":"Wegeners granulomatosis",
        "Option 3":"Giant cell arteritis",
        "Option 4":"Takayasu's arteritis",
        "Option 5":"Buergers disease",
        "Correct Answer":"Takayasu's arteritis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 78-year-old lady presents with symptoms of vision problems and chronic headaches. She notices that there is marked pain on the left-hand side of his face when she combs her hair. What is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Giant cell arteritis",
        "Option 2":"Wegener's granulomatosis",
        "Option 3":"Polyarteritis nodosa",
        "Option 4":"Takayasu's arteritis",
        "Option 5":"Buerger's disease",
        "Correct Answer":"Giant cell arteritis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"In cases of arterial mycotic aneurysm, what is the common causative organism?",
        "Option 1":"Streptococcus aureus",
        "Option 2":"Candida Albicans",
        "Option 3":"Aspergillus",
        "Option 4":"Staphylococcus aureus",
        "Option 5":"E.coli",
        "Correct Answer":"Staphylococcus aureus"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 45-lady started to complain of right leg pain and swelling, after traveling from Japan to the UK, her peripheral pulses were intact. Ultrasound revealed a large femoral venous thrombus. What is the best immediate intervention?",
        "Option 1":"Oral Warfarin",
        "Option 2":"IV Heparin",
        "Option 3":"Thrombolysis",
        "Option 4":"Aspirin",
        "Option 5":"IVC Filter",
        "Correct Answer":"IV Heparin"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 62-year-old man presents with a painful right lower limb. He underwent right  femoro- popliteal (below knee) bypass 18 months ago. On examination, the foot  is colder in comparison with the other side. Duplex examination showed that the  graft is blocked. What is the most likely cause?",
        "Option 1":"Aneurysmal dilatation",
        "Option 2":"Atheromatous plaques",
        "Option 3":"Neointimal hyperplasia",
        "Option 4":"Smooth muscle hyperplasia",
        "Option 5":"Arterial dissection",
        "Correct Answer":"Neointimal hyperplasia"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 23-year-old man is assaulted and has a stab injury to the right groin. First aid was done by cleaning the wound and applying a simple dressing. Six months later the  patient returns with a pulsatile swelling in the site of the injury. What is the most  probable diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Abscess",
        "Option 2":"False aneurysm of the femoral artery",
        "Option 3":"Lymphocele",
        "Option 4":"Mycotic aneurysm of the femoral artery",
        "Option 5":"Saphena varix",
        "Correct Answer":"False aneurysm of the femoral artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the ABPI measurements shown below is most likely to be found in a 45-  year-old man who develops calf pain after walking 600Y? On Examination, the  patient you find that he had a necrotic ulcer on the heal.",
        "Option 1":">1.2",
        "Option 2":"1",
        "Option 3":"0.7",
        "Option 4":"0.5",
        "Option 5":"0.3",
        "Correct Answer":"0.3"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the ABI measurements shown below is most likely to be developed in a 15-year history of DM and began to complain of calf pain after walking 600 yards?",
        "Option 1":">1.2",
        "Option 2":"1",
        "Option 3":"0.7",
        "Option 4":"0.5",
        "Option 5":"0.3",
        "Correct Answer":">1.2"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 35-year-old male came to the A&E with crushed limb. On examination, he is tachycardic at 120 b\/min with Bp at 110-70. His both bones of the leg are crushed with a completely avulsed neurovascular bundle and massive tissue loss. What is the best choice for the patient? A",
        "Option 1":"Wait the tissues to gain viability",
        "Option 2":"Interposition saphenous graft for popliteal artery repair",
        "Option 3":"Interposition synthetic graft for popliteal artery repair",
        "Option 4":"Primary Amputation",
        "Option 5":"Watchful waiting",
        "Correct Answer":"Primary Amputation"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 58-year-old diabetic male with chronic AF presented with sudden left lower limb  pain, by examination he has no distal pulsation below knee, what is the likely accepted cause of ischemia?",
        "Option 1":"Chronic thrombosis",
        "Option 2":"Embolic cause",
        "Option 3":"Peripheral hypoperfusion",
        "Option 4":"Normal Sequalae in old age",
        "Option 5":"Hypercoagulability",
        "Correct Answer":"Embolic cause"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Female patient has a swollen painful leg and diagnosed with DVT, what is the best initial investigation?",
        "Option 1":"Duplex on the venous system",
        "Option 2":"Compression ultrasound",
        "Option 3":"Plethysmography",
        "Option 4":"Venography",
        "Option 5":"Superficial US",
        "Correct Answer":"Compression ultrasound"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A patient presented with thigh pain after walking 100 m distance. It was diagnosed as a claudication pain. Arterial pathology at which level of the following may be  responsible for the symptoms?",
        "Option 1":"Common femoral artery",
        "Option 2":"Superficial femoral artery",
        "Option 3":"Popliteal artery",
        "Option 4":"Internal iliac artery",
        "Option 5":"Profunda femoris",
        "Correct Answer":"Common femoral artery"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What is the pathology of berry aneurysm in a 21-year-old boy?",
        "Option 1":"Atherosclerosis",
        "Option 2":"Congenital wall weakness",
        "Option 3":"Infection",
        "Option 4":"Hypertension",
        "Option 5":"Diabetes mellitus",
        "Correct Answer":"Congenital wall weakness"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 55-year-old male presented at your clinic complaining of chronic abdominal  pain. His US discovered abdominal aortic aneurysm measuring 4.7 cm, what Is the  best plane of action?",
        "Option 1":"Open surgical repair",
        "Option 2":"EVAR",
        "Option 3":"CT angiography",
        "Option 4":"Follow up with serial ultrasound",
        "Option 5":"MR angiography",
        "Correct Answer":"Follow up with serial ultrasound"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Which of the following is considered a positive test in cases of DVT?",
        "Option 1":"Homan test",
        "Option 2":"Hallux extension test",
        "Option 3":"Babinski sign",
        "Option 4":"Ankle reflex",
        "Option 5":"Patellar reflex",
        "Correct Answer":"Homan test"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 75-year-old male complained of ischemic manifestation in her lower limb with  distal gangrene in the toes following AAA repair, what is the most common cause  of his lower limb pathology?",
        "Option 1":"Arterial embolism",
        "Option 2":"Atherosclerosis",
        "Option 3":"Propagated Thrombus",
        "Option 4":"Foreign body aneurysm",
        "Option 5":"Vasospasm following surgery",
        "Correct Answer":"Arterial embolism"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A pregnant tall lady at 36-week gestation came with a sudden sharp chest pain.  Her father died of MI, what is the most likely diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Aortic dissection",
        "Option 2":"Pulmonary embolism",
        "Option 3":"Myocardial infarction",
        "Option 4":"Pericarditis",
        "Option 5":"Angina",
        "Correct Answer":"Aortic dissection"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65-year-old man underwent coronary artery bypass grafting one year ago using the using left internal-mammary artery. He now starts to complain of angina and chest pain with any minimal effort. Which of the following explains his new symptoms?",
        "Option 1":"Propagated thrombus inside the mammary artery",
        "Option 2":"Micro-emboli to the subclavian artery",
        "Option 3":"Stenosis of the subclavian artery at the level of the costocervical trunk",
        "Option 4":"Stenosis of the subclavian artery distal to the insertion of scalenus anterior",
        "Option 5":"Stenosis of the subclavian artery proximal to the first branch",
        "Correct Answer":"Stenosis of the subclavian artery proximal to the first branch"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 60-year-old male presented with back pain radiating to the loin which started while defecating. By examination he has a pulsatile abdominal mass. Also, Chest X-ray shows mediastinal widening. BP is 110\/70 with Heart rate 80. What is the next appropriate management?",
        "Option 1":"CT angiography scan",
        "Option 2":"Immediate transfer to theatre",
        "Option 3":"Ultrasound examination",
        "Option 4":"Prepare for elective surgery",
        "Option 5":"Follow up as outpatient",
        "Correct Answer":"CT angiography scan"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 60-year-old patient has no significant past medical history and a 99% stenosis of  the left and a 60% stenosis of the right internal carotid artery. What is the most  appropriate diagnostic option to confirm the extent and size of the occlusion?",
        "Option 1":"Right carotid endarterectomy",
        "Option 2":"Left carotid endarterectomy",
        "Option 3":"Right carotid artery stenting",
        "Option 4":"Left carotid artery stenting",
        "Option 5":"Carotid Angiography",
        "Correct Answer":"Carotid Angiography"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 58 year old cardiac male patient complains of attacks of atrial fibrillation present  with a 3-hour history of pain and white left lower limb. Which of the following is  the best management option?",
        "Option 1":"Thrombolysis",
        "Option 2":"LMWH",
        "Option 3":"Warfarin",
        "Option 4":"Femoral embolectomy",
        "Option 5":"Aspirin",
        "Correct Answer":"Femoral embolectomy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"48.What 's the best long-term management for post-phlebitic syndrome?",
        "Option 1":"Heparin",
        "Option 2":"Long life warfarin",
        "Option 3":"Lower limb stocking bandage",
        "Option 4":"Vitamin C",
        "Option 5":"Antibiotics",
        "Correct Answer":"Lower limb stocking bandage"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 50-year-old man presents with a three-month history of buttock pain after  walking 50 meters. On direct questioning he admits having impotence. He smokes  20 cigarettes a day. What is the most accepted diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Bilateral superficial femoral artery occlusion",
        "Option 2":"Occlusion of a common iliac artery",
        "Option 3":"Occlusion of an external iliac artery",
        "Option 4":"Occlusion of both common iliac arteries",
        "Option 5":"None of the above",
        "Correct Answer":"Occlusion of both common iliac arteries"
    },
    {
        "Question":"What of The Following is associated with Raynaud Phenomenon?",
        "Option 1":"Atherosclerosis",
        "Option 2":"Hyperthyroidism",
        "Option 3":"Rheumatoid Arthritis",
        "Option 4":"Embolism",
        "Option 5":"Hypertension",
        "Correct Answer":"Rheumatoid Arthritis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 35-year-old patient with regular cardiac rhythm and no History Of peripheral  vascular disease. He presented with right leg pulseless especially when it is full extended, and the other Leg has bounding popliteal pulsation. What Is the most  probable diagnosis?",
        "Option 1":"Embolism from the atrial myxoma",
        "Option 2":"Thrombosed popliteal artery aneurysm",
        "Option 3":"Thrombosis of femoral artery",
        "Option 4":"Popliteal artery entrapment syndrome",
        "Option 5":"Popliteal aneurysm",
        "Correct Answer":"Popliteal artery entrapment syndrome"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 65-year-old diabetic patient, who is previously well, presented now with blackish discoloration of the big toe over the past 1 month. What Is The most probable  Pathology?",
        "Option 1":"Iliofemoral atherosclerosis",
        "Option 2":"Acute Embolism",
        "Option 3":"Acute on top of chronic ischemia",
        "Option 4":"Burger Disease",
        "Option 5":"Takayasu arteritis",
        "Correct Answer":"Iliofemoral atherosclerosis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 74-year-old, man presents with a pulsatile swelling in his abdomen. The principal abnormality within the wall of arterial aneurysms is loss of which structure?",
        "Option 1":"Adventitial collagen",
        "Option 2":"Adventitial elastin",
        "Option 3":"Intimal collagen",
        "Option 4":"Intimal elastin",
        "Option 5":"Medial elastin",
        "Correct Answer":"Medial elastin"
    },
    {
        "Question":"The following drugs are used to treat patients with peripheral vascular disease. They all reduce the rate of myocardial infarction and stroke except which of the following?",
        "Option 1":"A.C.E inhibitors",
        "Option 2":"Antihypertensive medication",
        "Option 3":"Aspirin",
        "Option 4":"Cholesterol lowering drugs",
        "Option 5":"Oxypentifylline",
        "Correct Answer":"Oxypentifylline"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 56-year-old man with documented Type 1 diabetes mellitus presents to the Surgical outpatient clinic with 3 months history of right leg pain brought on by walking 50 meters. He has no history of back pain. He has been a smoker for 10 years (10 cigarettes a day). He still on his alcohol consumption to be 30 units per week. On clinical examination, significant findings include no right foot pulses with altered sensation on dorsum of the right toot. What is the most likely diagnosis from the following list?",
        "Option 1":"Autonomic neuropathy",
        "Option 2":"Femoral-popliteal stenosis",
        "Option 3":"Neuropathic joint disease",
        "Option 4":"Polyneuropathy",
        "Option 5":"Radiculopathy",
        "Correct Answer":"Femoral-popliteal stenosis"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 76-year-old man presents with a painful left leg. The pain began suddenly and with no history. On examination, he has a white left leg with no palpable femoral pulse and loss of sensation. The pulses in the contralateral limb are normal. It is now 3 hours since the pain first started. What is the best course of action?",
        "Option 1":"Primary amputation",
        "Option 2":"Transfemoral embolectomy with prophylactic fasciotomy",
        "Option 3":"Transfemoral embolectomy without prophylactic fasciotomy",
        "Option 4":"Angiogram",
        "Option 5":"Systemic heparin",
        "Correct Answer":"Transfemoral embolectomy without prophylactic fasciotomy"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 56-year-old man presents with a painful left leg. The pain has been present for the past 8 hours although it has also been present (though less severe) about a week ago. At that stage he noted that his hallux had turned blue. This resolved spontaneously. On examination, he has a weakly palpable femoral pulse on the affected side but no pulses palpable distal to this. His sensation is mildly impaired. What is the best course of action?",
        "Option 1":"Trans popliteal embolectomy without prophylactic fasciotomy",
        "Option 2":"Trans popliteal embolectomy with prophylactic fasciotomy",
        "Option 3":"Angiogram",
        "Option 4":"Systemic heparin",
        "Option 5":"Follow up",
        "Correct Answer":"Angiogram"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 78-year-old lady presented with a severely painful left leg. On examination  she has no palpable pulses, and the limb is cold and mottled. The mottling does not blanch with pressure. What is the best course of action?",
        "Option 1":"Primary amputation",
        "Option 2":"Angiogram",
        "Option 3":"Systemic heparin infusion",
        "Option 4":"Peripheral thrombolysis",
        "Option 5":"Primary amputation",
        "Correct Answer":null
    },
    {
        "Question":"Fracture Shaft of Femur was reduced, and implant placed. At the end of  operation, you note that the lower leg seems pale with reduced pulse. What is  the best next step in management?",
        "Option 1":"Re-exploration of the wound",
        "Option 2":"Embolectomy",
        "Option 3":"CT Angiography",
        "Option 4":"Follow up",
        "Option 5":"IV heparin",
        "Correct Answer":"Re-exploration of the wound"
    },
    {
        "Question":"Male patient 35 years old accidentally discovered to have a popliteal aneurysm size 2.5 cm causing no complication, what is the best course of action?",
        "Option 1":"CT Angiography",
        "Option 2":"Surgical Removal",
        "Option 3":"Angioplasty",
        "Option 4":"Follow up",
        "Option 5":"Surgical Removal",
        "Correct Answer":null
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 72-year-old male underwent aortic aneurysm repair last night, today the patient  is complaining of nausea and vomiting. His investigations showed elevated blood urea and creatinine with K at 5.6 mmol. What is the best immediate management?",
        "Option 1":"Give bolus of saline",
        "Option 2":"Hemodialysis",
        "Option 3":"Insulin glucose solution",
        "Option 4":"Measurement of abdominal pressure",
        "Option 5":"Renal Ultrasound",
        "Correct Answer":"Measurement of abdominal pressure"
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 35 lady underwent bariatric surgery recently and after a discussion with  hematology registrar he recommended a 2-week oral anticoagulant. As the  patient has phobia to needles what is the anticoagulant of choice?",
        "Option 1":"Warfarin 5mg",
        "Option 2":"Clopidogrel",
        "Option 3":"Rivaroxaban",
        "Option 4":"Aspirin",
        "Option 5":"Rivaroxaban",
        "Correct Answer":null
    },
    {
        "Question":"A 29 year old man used to smoke about 15 cigarettes per day without any other medical or surgical history. He presented complaining of dry gangrene of his right big toe. He alleged a 2 year history of claudication, what is the most accepted cause?",
        "Option 1":"Diabetic neuropathy",
        "Option 2":"Neurological claudication",
        "Option 3":"Burger disease",
        "Option 4":"Femoral artery atherosclerosis",
        "Option 5":"Tibial vessels calcifications",
        "Correct Answer":"Burger disease"
    }
]